hey everybody welcome to this b1 english
listening practice video you can use
this video to practice your listening
and comprehension as i speak before we
start remember to download my listening
time podcast and become a listening time
member at
patreon.com listening time to receive my
listening practice seminars so today i'm
going to talk about thanksgiving we just
recently celebrated this famous american
holiday so i thought it'd be a good
topic for this video so first of all
what are the origins of thanksgiving
where did it come from well to be honest
there isn't really a whole lot that we
can draw from to know that much about
the first thanksgiving actually there's
really only one short description
written by a man named edward winslow
regarding the first thanksgiving feast
but from what we do know the story goes
a little something like this in 1621 the
pilgrims living in plymouth which was
located in the modern day state of
massachusetts held a feast with the
wampanoag people which were a native
american group that lived in the area at
that time this feast was a celebration
of the native americans first successful
corn harvest and they decided to invite
some of their native american allies to
join in nobody can say for sure what
food was served but it's safe to say
that it probably didn't bear much
resemblance to the thanksgiving food we
eat nowadays so let's go through several
traditional thanksgiving dishes that
you'll find on tables across the u.s
firstly and most importantly you have
the thanksgiving turkey this animal has
become the iconic image of thanksgiving
and most families wouldn't be able to
imagine a thanksgiving without it
besides turkey another essential is the
stuffing this is a mix of herbs spices
veggies and breadcrumbs that are stuffed
into the turkey before cooking a good
thanksgiving meal needs a good stuffing
another essential side dish is the
cranberry sauce which provides a good
sweet contrast to the savory taste of
the turkey and a few other traditional
side dishes include mashed potatoes and
gravy green bean casserole and dinner
rolls and for dessert people like to eat
pies such as apple pie pumpkin pie and
pecan pie alright so besides food what
else is there to know about thanksgiving
well as the name implies it's supposed
to be a day when people give thanks for
the blessings in their lives so for
example some families go around the
dinner table and have each person say
one thing that they're thankful for i
like this tradition because it allows us
to take a step back and reflect on the
good in our lives we get so caught up in
the stress of our everyday lives and all
the bad things that happen to us so it's
nice to be able to put all that aside
and acknowledge the blessings on a
lighter note another common thing that
people like to do on thanksgiving is
watch and play football for some reason
thanksgiving has become a big football
day in america so people can watch a
couple games while they're cooking or
the adults and kids can play a game in
the backyard while they're waiting for
the big feast one other important thing
about thanksgiving is that it's the day
before black friday this is the biggest
shopping day of the year in the u.s many
people start their black friday shopping
at midnight after thanksgiving many
stores open their doors at 12 a.m on
this day so a lot of people line up
hours beforehand to make sure they get
first dibs on the best deals a lot of
people criticize the fact that stores
open at this time because it tends to
take away a little bit from the
thanksgiving celebration and it adds a
little bit more stress to the holiday
i'm not a big shopper so black friday
doesn't really mean much to me but for
other people and for companies it's an
important day okay now i'm going to ask
you a few questions to see how well you
understood number one in what year was
the first thanksgiving celebrated number
two what type of dessert is the most
common on thanksgiving and number three
what's one popular thanksgiving
tradition alright before we go remember
to download the listening time podcast
and become a listening time member at
patreon.com listeningtime so you can
receive my listening practice seminars
and of course subscribe to the channel
and click on the bell i'll see you next
time
[Music]